cellartracker.com 2019-04-27

# Privacy Policy - CellarTracker

**Last Changes to Privacy Policy: February 12, 2019**

CellarTracker! LLC (collectively “CellarTracker” or “we”, “us”, or “our”) is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information when you interact with the cellartracker.com website and mobile applications (“Sites”). This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains the kinds of information we may gather from your use of the Sites; why we gather your information; what we use your personal information for; when we might disclose your personal information; and how you can manage your personal information.

This Privacy Policy applies to CellarTracker’s websites, mobile applications, emails we send, as well as information we collect when you interact with us through our services and other websites.

**By visiting the Sites, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of the Sites and our affiliate websites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Policy retroactively, we will provide you with notice of the modifications or amendments.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don’t see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at [support@cellartracker.com](mailto:support@cellartracker.com).

CellarTracker adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to the Sites.

### Our Privacy Policy is simple: Except as disclosed below, we don't sell, barter, give away, or rent your personal information to any company outside of or not affiliated with CellarTracker.

### Information You Give Us

The Sites include features or services that permit you to enter contact information and other information about you (“Information You Give Us”). We collect and store any information you enter on the Sites. This includes:

  * Information you may provide in connection with your creation of an account, including your First Name, Last Name, City, State, Email Address, and Username.
  * Information you provide in connection with making your subscription payment.
  * Information or data you provide by interacting in our online forum or by commenting on content posted on the Sites. The content, such as tasting notes, may be visible to other users of the Sites.
  * Information you provide when you interact with us via social media, including any posts, pictures, videos and messages which you submit to us either via our social media sites (including by use of hashtags associated with us) or the Sites.
  * Information you provide from other sources, such as third party wine reviewers that you subscribe to, to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence and any contact information provided.

_CellarTracker does not process or store credit card information._ When you submit a subscription payment, members are connected with a third party online payment platform, Braintree Payments, which processes the credit card transaction and sends us confirmation of payment and limited details about your payment method. Braintree Payments uses industry-standard encryption and secure web pages for transmission of credit card information to keep your information secure, accurate, current, and complete. For more information on Braintree Payments, please visit their website.

### Information We Collect Automatically

When you interact with the Sites, certain information about your use of the Sites is automatically collected. Much of this information is collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies, as well as through your web browser or device. Any or all activities with regard to collecting usage information may be performed on our behalf by third-parties (see Additional Information About Third Party Cookies below). This includes:

  * Details of your visits to the Sites and information generated in the course of the use the Sites including, but not limited to, server data, search terms and results, server logs and other communication data, the resources that you access, and how you reached the Sites.
  * Details regarding the device you use to access the Sites, including, where available, your IP address, operating system, and browser type.
  * Information about how you interact with our ads, newsletters and email notifications, including whether you open or click links in any correspondence.

We may use the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Sites so we can provide you with the best service and grow our business.
  * To communicate with you, including responding to your inquiries, fulfilling your requests, and sending you information about products, services, and promotional offers.
  * To analyze website usage and enhance the operation of the Sites.
  * To detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be fraudulent or illegal.
  * To enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

### Sharing of Aggregated Data

We may create analyses using aggregated, de-identified data and share these analyses at our discretion to provide statistical "ratings" information to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Sites. We may also use or share aggregated data (or other information, other than personal information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. These third parties will not be able to relate this data to identifiable individuals.

### Third-Party Agents

We engage third party service providers to perform functions on our behalf such as: hosting, content management, analytics, anti-scraping prevention, etc. Third Party Agents are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Sites.

### Law Enforcement and Legal Process

We may also use or disclose information about you if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Sites; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Sites or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the our personal safety or the personal safety of our affiliates, agents, the users of the Sites, or the public.

### Social Media Platforms

Where you choose to interact with us through social media, your interaction with these programs typically allows the third party to collect some information about you through cookies they place on your device and other tracking mechanisms. In some cases, the third party may recognize you through its cookies even when you do not interact with their application. Please visit the third parties’ respective privacy policies to better understand their data collection practices and controls they make available to you.

### What Happens When I Link To or From Another Website?

The Sites may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of CellarTracker or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy for CellarTracker do not apply to information gathered through these other websites. These other websites may also send their own cookies to you, collect your data or solicit your personal information. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave the Sites and read the privacy policies of each and every website that you visit.

### Change of Ownership or Corporate Organization

We may change ownership or corporate organization while providing the Sites and services. As a result, please be aware that we may transfer your information to another service that is affiliated with us or with which we have merged. Under such circumstances, CellarTracker would, to the extent possible, require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.

### Transfer of Data

If you use the Sites outside of the United States, you understand that we may collect, process, and store information about you in the United States and other countries. The laws in the U.S. regarding personal information may be different from the laws of your country. Any such transfers will comply with safeguards as required by relevant law. By using the Sites, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your data.

We use a combination of physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect the information we collect through the Sites. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you. While we use these precautions to safeguard your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of the networks, systems, servers, devices, and databases we operate or that are operated on our behalf.

The Sites are published in the United States of America. We make every effort to protect the personal information of all users of the Sites. We attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to the services.

If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, the following information applies:

_Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing_ : As explained above, we process personal data in various ways depending upon your interaction with the Sites. We process personal data on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform our agreement to provide our services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the Sites and our services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedom related to data privacy.

_Right to lodge a complaint_ : Users that reside in the EEA or Switzerland have the right to lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority concerned. Contact details for data protection authorities are available here.

_Transfers_ : Personal information we collect may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates or subcontractors maintain facilities. We will ensure that transfers of personal information to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards as described in Article 46 of the GDPR.

_Your Rights_ : Residents of the EEA and Switzerland are entitled to rights under Chapter III of the EU General Data Protection Regulation or Section 2 of the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection with respect to the processing of your personal information, including rights to request erasure of personal information or object to our processing of personal information. In order to verify your identity, we may require you to provide us with personal information prior to accessing any records containing information about you. With respect to these rights, you should contact us by email at [support@cellartracker.com](mailto:support@cellartracker.com).

You may always opt-out of receiving future e-mail messages and newsletters from CellarTracker. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us by modifying your notification settings at <https://www.cellartracker.com/alerts.asp>. We also give you access to a broad range of information about your account to permit you to correct or update personal information that you have previously provided to us at <https://www.cellartracker.com/editprofile.asp>. You can also send us a message at [support@cellartracker.com](mailto:support@cellartracker.com).

Residents of the State of California have the right to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please send an e-mail to [support@cellartracker.com](mailto:support@cellartracker.com).

CellarTracker relies on partners to provide many features of the Sites and services. In order to do this, we provide our partners with data about your use of the Sites and other websites.

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * _Site Operations_ : Enabling features that are necessary for providing you the services on the Sites, such as identifying you as being signed in, remembering your preferences and recent searches, and the number of times you have been shown an advertisement.
  * _Analytics_ : Allowing us to understand how our services are being used, track site performance and make improvements.
  * _Personalized Advertising_ : Delivering tailored advertising based on your preferences or interests across services and devices and measuring the effectiveness of ads.

**The personal information from the following users is not provided to our partners for the purposes of personalized advertising:**

  * Users in the EEA and Switzerland;
  * Users who are actively logged on to the Sites; and
  * Users who only use our mobile app.

Below is a list of these partners with links to more information their use of your data and how to exercise your options regarding tracking.

Category | Partner | Further Information  
---|---|---  
Analytics | Bugsnag | [Privacy Policy](https://docs.bugsnag.com/legal/privacy-policy/)  
Analytics | HelpScout | [Privacy Policy](https://www.helpscout.net/company/legal/privacy/)  
Analytics, Personalized Advertising | Google | [How Google uses information from sites or apps that use our services](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)  
Personalized Advertising | Sortable | [Privacy Policy](https://www.sortable.com/privacy-policy/)  
Security | Stackpath | [Privacy Policy](https://www.stackpath.com/legal/privacy-statement)  
  
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to disable or reject cookies. If you delete your cookies or if you set your browser to decline cookies, some features of the services may not be available, work, or work as designed.

You can learn more about ad serving companies and the options available to limit their collection and use of your information by visiting the websites for the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), and the [European Interactive Digital Advertising Initiative](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Similarly, you can learn about your options to opt-out of mobile app tracking by certain advertising networks through your device settings and by resetting the advertiser ID on your Apple or Android device.

Please note that opting-out of advertising networks services does not mean that you will not receive advertising while using the Sites or on other websites, nor will it prevent the receipt of interest-based advertising from third parties that do not participate in these programs. It will, however, exclude you from interest-based advertising conducted through participating networks, as provided by their policies and choice mechanisms. If you delete your cookies, you may also delete your opt-out preferences.

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post any changes, and such changes will become effective when they are posted. Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of any changes will mean you accept those changes.

We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use the Sites in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy. We will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information we have previously collected without your express consent.
